<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Torb on Torb Lunde Miranda</title>
    <link>https://www.torb.no/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Torb on Torb Lunde Miranda</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.torb.no/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.torb.no/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.torb.no/about/</guid>
      <description>Front-end developer and interaction designer I’m a front-end developer and interaction designer. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on everything from websites, web-apps, interactive installations to e-learning courses.
Experience and education Currently I work as a web developer and designer for Omega 365, and I have also done UI design, information architecture among other things for them in the past.
I&amp;rsquo;ve also worked for Back where I designed and programmed interactive installations, games and other interactive experiences for museums and visitation centers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Omega 365</title>
      <link>https://www.torb.no/projects/omega-365-webpage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.torb.no/projects/omega-365-webpage/</guid>
      <description>Omega 365 homepage Information Architecture, Web Design, Front-End Development, Bootstrap 5, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, C#, Appframe I worked on a comprehensive redesign of Omega 365&amp;rsquo;s corporate homepage, a company with over 1,500 employees from around the world. Here I worked on everything from the information architecture to concrete implementation. I also coordinated with developers on improvements to Omega&amp;rsquo;s proprietary content management system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>House of Salmon</title>
      <link>https://www.torb.no/projects/house-of-salmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.torb.no/projects/house-of-salmon/</guid>
      <description>House of Salmon Interaction Design, Visual Design, Front-End Development, Game Development, Unity, C#, React, TypeScript, Android, Java, Capacitor, Craft CMS, Phidgets House of Salmon is a visitation for aquaculture. Here students and other can learn about how salmon farming works and it‘s history.
While working for Back I designed and programmed experiences for several interactive installations and smartphone.
This included a phone app that allows participants to register points, activate various installations and play mini games connected to various installations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Periodic System Wall</title>
      <link>https://www.torb.no/projects/periodic-wall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.torb.no/projects/periodic-wall/</guid>
      <description>Periodic System Wall Interaction Design, UI Design, Front-End Development, React, TypeScript, Craft CMS, Phidgets Together with colleagues in Back I worked on a wall of the periodic table for Norwegian Mining Museum. This installation allowed visitors to learn about specific elements or groups of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web-based editor</title>
      <link>https://www.torb.no/projects/omega-web-based-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.torb.no/projects/omega-web-based-editor/</guid>
      <description>Omega 365&amp;rsquo;s web-based editor Front-end Development, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery Large parts of Omega 365&amp;rsquo;s developer tools are entirely web based. I worked on the UI design and front-end code for the editor and IDE used to create user facing webapps and websites. This was also used as a basis for other tools such as a SQL management tool. I also created tools for autogenerating code used both as a learning tool and for speeding up development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://www.torb.no/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.torb.no/contact/</guid>
      <description> E-mail GitHub Twitter LinkedIn  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Phidgets with React</title>
      <link>https://www.torb.no/blog/phidgets-with-react/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.torb.no/blog/phidgets-with-react/</guid>
      <description>Using Phidgets with React 14. November 2022
Phidgets is a system for sensors, input devices and controllers of things like LED or motors. In this tutorial I‘ll explain gotchas and generally how to use it with React. For the impatient: the gotchas you need to be aware of is:
 Use the JavaScript library for browsers, not the NPM one. Use hooks to interact with the Phidgets library, as it’s very OOP oriented.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
