<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Torb on Torb Lunde Miranda</title>
    <link>https://www.torb.no/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Torb on Torb Lunde Miranda</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.torb.no/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.torb.no/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.torb.no/about/</guid>
      <description>Designing and developing experiences I’m a front-end developer, interaction designer and creative technologist. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on everything from websites, web-apps, interactive installations to e-learning courses.
Experience and education Currently I work as a web developer and designer for Omega 365, and I have also done UI design, information architecture among other things for them in the past.
I&amp;rsquo;ve also worked for Back where I designed and programmed interactive installations, games and other interactive experiences for museums and visitation centers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Omega 365</title>
      <link>https://www.torb.no/projects/omega-365-webpage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.torb.no/projects/omega-365-webpage/</guid>
      <description>Omega 365 homepage Information Architecture, Web Design, Front-End Development, Bootstrap 5, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, C#, Appframe I worked on a comprehensive redesign of Omega 365&amp;rsquo;s corporate homepage, a company with over 1,500 employees from around the world. Here I worked on everything from the information architecture to concrete implementation. I also coordinated with developers on improvements to Omega&amp;rsquo;s proprietary content management system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Periodic System Wall</title>
      <link>https://www.torb.no/projects/periodic-wall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.torb.no/projects/periodic-wall/</guid>
      <description>Periodic System Wall Interaction Design, UI Design, Front-End Development, React, TypeScript, Craft CMS, Phidgets Together with colleagues in Back I worked on a wall of the periodic table for Norwegian Mining Museum. This installation allowed visitors to learn about specific elements or groups of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>House of Salmon</title>
      <link>https://www.torb.no/projects/house-of-salmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.torb.no/projects/house-of-salmon/</guid>
      <description>House of Salmon Interaction Design, Visual Design, Front-End Development, Game Development, Unity, C#, React, TypeScript, Android, Java, Capacitor, Craft CMS, Phidgets House of Salmon is a visitation for aquaculture. Here students and other can learn about how salmon farming works and it‘s history.
While working for Back I designed and programmed experiences for several interactive installations and smartphone.
This included a phone app that allows participants to register points, activate various installations and play mini games connected to various installations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rockheim Hall of Fame</title>
      <link>https://www.torb.no/projects/rockheim-hall-of-fame/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.torb.no/projects/rockheim-hall-of-fame/</guid>
      <description>Rockheim Hall of Fame User Interface Design, Information Architecture, Visual Design At Back I designed the touch screen experience for Rockheim Hall of Fame. In this screen visitors are able to learn about the inductees and their place in the history of Norwegian popular music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magical drawing installation</title>
      <link>https://www.torb.no/projects/magical-drawing-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.torb.no/projects/magical-drawing-installation/</guid>
      <description>Magical drawing installation for kids Creative Technology, Prototyping, C++, openFrameworks, Processing, Arduino, Grove System While studying at University of Oslo I collaborated on a project to prototype interactive installations for Oslo Children‘s Museum. Together with my group I iterated on ideas, eventually landing on an experience where kids could draw on magical screen alone or with others. When several used it together the installation implicitly encouraged collaboration.
This drawing machine controlled by holding hands over distance sensors by ”pushing” in the pair the direction you want the virtual pen to go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sound Painter</title>
      <link>https://www.torb.no/projects/sound-painter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.torb.no/projects/sound-painter/</guid>
      <description>Sound Painter Creative Technology, Prototyping, Processing For Oslo Children‘s Museum in co-operation with Nora Tessem I created a prototype for an interactive installations that let‘s people make noise to throw virtual paint at a screen. The colour of the paint is based on the pitch of the sound and the intensity matches the volume.
Kids are often expected to sit and be quiet. We noticed that many of them found it especially fun that they where supposed to make a lot of noise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web-based editor</title>
      <link>https://www.torb.no/projects/omega-web-based-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.torb.no/projects/omega-web-based-editor/</guid>
      <description>Omega 365&amp;rsquo;s web-based editor Front-end Development, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery Large parts of Omega 365&amp;rsquo;s developer tools are entirely web based. I worked on the UI design and front-end code for the editor and IDE used to create user facing webapps and websites. This was also used as a basis for other tools such as a SQL management tool. I also created tools for autogenerating code used both as a learning tool and for speeding up development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://www.torb.no/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.torb.no/contact/</guid>
      <description> E-mail GitHub Twitter LinkedIn  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Phidgets with React</title>
      <link>https://www.torb.no/blog/phidgets-with-react/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.torb.no/blog/phidgets-with-react/</guid>
      <description>Using Phidgets with React 14. November 2021
Phidgets is a system for sensors, input devices and controllers of things like LED or motors. In this tutorial I‘ll explain gotchas and generally how to use it with React. For the impatient: the gotchas you need to be aware of is:
 Use the JavaScript library for browsers, not the NPM one. Use hooks to interact with the Phidgets library, as it’s very OOP oriented.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
